A Guide to the Policy Office Clemency Files of Governor James S. Gilmore, 1998-2001
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Policy Office Clemency Files of Governor James S. Gilmore, 1998-2001
The Library of Virginia
40166
9.55 cu. ft. (27 boxes)
Virginia Governor (1998-2002: Gilmore)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Records are restricted (public access and photoduplication) for 75 years after date of record creation per Code of Virginia 42.1-78.
Acquisition Information
Transferred on 17 November 2002 by James S. Gilmore, Richmond, Va.
Scope and Content
This collection contains the clemency records of Virginians executed during Governor James S. Gilmore's Administration (1998-2002). Most, but not all, clemency files contain a clemency petition (either a letter or a formal document), legal files (trial transcripts, court rulings, execution orders, etc.) and correspondence from interested parties. Some also include handwritten notes about the petition by the Counselor to the Governor (David E. Anderson, 1998-1999 and Walter S. Felton, Jr., 1999-2002) and/or Governor, meeting notes between the Counselor and attorneys for the condemned and police and prison files. This collection is housed in 27 boxes and is arranged chronologically by date of execution. Dates of record-keeping activity: 1998-2001.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically:
1998
1999
2000
2001
Contents List
- 1998, Extent: 10 boxes. (Box 1-10)
  1998 clemency files include: Tony Albert Mackall (executed 1998 February 10), Douglas McArthur Buchanan (executed 1998 March 18), Ronald Watkins (executed 1998 March 25), Angel Breard (executed 1998 April 14), Dennis Wayne Eaton (executed 1998 June 18), Danny Lee King (executed 1998 July 23), Lance Antonio Chandler (executed 1998 August 20), Johnile L. Dubois (executed 1998 August 31), Kenneth Manuel Stewart, Jr. (executed 1998 September 23), Dwayne Allen Wright (executed 1998 October 14), Ronald Fitzgerald (executed 1998 October 21), Kenneth Wilson (executed 1998 November 17), and Kevin Dewayne Cardwell (executed 1998 December 3).
  - Mackall, Tony Albert, Executed 1998 February 10 - Correspondence, News Clippings and Meeting Notes, 1998 February (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Mackall, Tony Albert, Executed 1998 February 10 - Commutation Request, 1998 January 28 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mackall, Tony Albert, Executed 1998 February 10 - Evidence presented by Mackall to jury at the penalty stage of trial (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mackall, Tony Albert, Executed 1998 February 10 - Constituent Correspondence, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Buchanan, Douglas McArthur, Executed 1998 March 18 - Legal documents and related correspondence, 1998 March (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Buchanan, Douglas McArthur, Executed 1998 March 18 - Legal documents and related correspondence, 1998 March (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Buchanan, Douglas McArthur, Executed 1998 March 18 - Constituent Correspondence, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Watkins, Ronald, Executed 1998 March 25 - Correspondence, News Clippings and Meeting Notes, 1998 March (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Watkins, Ronald, Executed 1998 March 25 - "A Plea for the Life of Ronald L. Watkins" submitted by William S. Geimer, Professor of Law, Washington and Lee University, 1998 March 19 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Watkins, Ronald, Executed 1998 March 25 - Constituent Correspondence, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Breard, Angel, Executed 1998 April 14 - Correspondence, Legal Files and News Clippings, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Breard, Angel, Executed 1998 April 14 - Correspondence, Legal Files and News Clippings, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Breard, Angel, Executed 1998 April 14 - Correspondence, Legal Files and News Clippings, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Breard, Angel, Executed 1998 April 14 - Correspondence, Legal Files and News Clippings, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Breard, Angel, Executed 1998 April 14 - Petition for Executive Clemency, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Breard, Angel, Executed 1998 April 14 - Constituent Correspondence (United States), 1998 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Breard, Angel, Executed 1998 April 14 - Constituent Correspondence (Pro, United States), 1998 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Brerad, Angel, Executed 1998 April 14 - Constituent Correspondence (Foreign), 1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Breard, Angel, Executed 1998 April 14 - Constituent Correspondence (Pro, Con and Foreign), 1998 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Breard, Angel, Executed 1998 April 14 - Constituent Correspondence (Pro, Con and Foreign), 1998 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Breard, Angel, Executed 1998 April 14 - Constituent Correspondence (Pro, Con and Foreign), 1998 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Eaton, Dennis Wayne, Executed 1998 June 18 - Correspondence, Legal Files and News Clippings, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Eaton, Dennis Wayne, Executed 1998 June 18 - Capital Case (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Eaton, Dennis Wayne, Executed 1998 June 18 - Constituent Correspondence, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - King, Danny Lee, Executed 1998 July 23 - Correspondence, Legal Files and Meeting notes, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - King, Danny Lee, Executed 1998 July 23 - Constituent Correspondence, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Chandler, Lance Antonio, Executed 1998 August 20 - Correspondence, Legal Files, Meeting Notes and News Clippings, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Chandler, Lance Antonio, Executed 1998 August 20 - Constituent Correspondence, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Dubois, Johnile L., Executed 1998 August 31 - Correspondence, Legal Files, Meeting Notes and News Clippings, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Dubois, Johnile L., Executed 1998 August 31 - Constituent Correspondence, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Stewart, Jr., Kenneth Manuel, Executed 1998 September 23 - Correspondence, Legal Files, Meeting Notes and News Clippings, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Stewart, Jr., Kenneth Manuel, Executed 1998 September 23 - Constituent Correspondence, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Stewart, Jr., Kenneth Manuel, Executed 1998 September 23 - Forensic Psychiatric Evaluation of Kenneth Stewart (part one) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Stewart, Jr., Kenneth Manuel, Executed 1998 September 23 - Forensic Psychiatric Evaluation of Kenneth Stewart (part two) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Stewart, Jr., Kenneth Manuel, Executed 1998 September 23 - Forensic Psychiatric Evaluation of Kenneth Stewart (part three) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Stewart, Jr., Kenneth Manuel, Executed 1998 September 23 - Trial Transcript, 1991 (part one) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Stewart, Jr., Kenneth Manuel, Executed 1998 September 23 - Trial Transcript, 1992 January 17 and February 4(part two) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Stewart, Jr., Kenneth Manuel, Executed 1998 September 23 - Trial Transcript, 1992 February 4 (continued) (part three) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Stewart, Jr., Kenneth Manuel, Executed 1998 September 23 - Trial Transcript, 1992 February 5 (part four) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Stewart, Jr., Kenneth Manuel, Executed 1998 September 23 - Trial Transcript, 1992 February 6 (part five) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Stewart, Jr., Kenneth Manuel, Executed 1998 September 23 - Trial Transcript, 1992 February 7 (part six) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Stewart, Jr., Kenneth Manuel, Executed 1998 September 23 - Trial Transcript, 1992 February 11 (volume one) (part seven) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Stewart, Jr., Kenneth Manuel, Executed 1998 September 23 - Trial Transcript, 1992 February 11 (volume two) and 1992 May 5 (sentencing) (part eight) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Wright, Dwayne Allen, Executed 1998 October 14 - Clemency Petition (part one) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Wright, Dwayne Allen, Executed 1998 October 14 - Clemency Petition (part two) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Wright, Dwayne Allen, Executed 1998 October 14 - Clemency Petition (part three) (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Wright, Dwayne Allen, Executed 1998 October 14 - Correspondence, Legal Files, Meeting Notes and News Clippings, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Wright, Dwayne Allen, Executed 1998 October 14 - Correspondence, Legal Files, Meeting Notes and News Clippings, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Wright, Dwayne Allen, Executed 1998 October 14 - Constituent Correspondence, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Wright, Dwayne Allen, Executed 1998 October 14 - Constituent Correspondence, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Wright, Dwayne Allen, Executed 1998 October 14 - Constituent Correspondence, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Wright, Dwayne Allen, Executed 1998 October 14 - Constituent Correspondence, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Wright, Dwayne Allen, Executed 1998 October 14 - Constituent Correspondence, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Fitzgerald, Ronald, Executed 1998 October 21 (No Clemency Request Made) - Correspondence, Legal Files, Newspaper Clippings and Constituent Correspondence, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Wilson, Kenneth, Executed 1998 November 17 - Videotape containing Clemency Plea from Wilson's family (5 minutes) (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Wilson, Kenneth, Executed 1998 November 17 - Clemency Petition, Correspondence, Meeting Notes and Legal Files, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Wilson, Kenneth, Executed 1998 November 17 - Clemency Petition and Legal Files, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Wilson, Kenneth, Executed 1998 November 17 - Constituent Correspondence, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Cardwell, Kevin Dewayne, Executed 1998 December 3 - (No Clemency Request Made) Correspondence and Constituent Correspondence, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- 1999, Extent: 7 boxes. (Box 10-17)
  1999 clemency files include: Mark A. Sheppard (executed 1999 January 20), Tony Leslie Fray (executed 1999 February 4), George Quesinberry (executed 1999 March 9), David Lee Fisher (executed 1999 March 25), Carl Chichester (executed 1999 April 13), Arthur Jenkins (executed 1999 April 20), Eric Payne (executed 1999 April 28), Ronald Dale Yeatts (executed 1999 April 29), Tommy David Stricker (executed 1999 July 21), Marlon Dwayne Williams (executed 1999 August 17), Everett Ray Mueller (executed 1999 September 16), Jason Matthew Joseph (executed 1999 October 19), Thomas Lee Royal, Jr. (executed 1999 November 9), and Andre Graham (executed 1999 December 9).
  - Sheppard, Mark A., Executed 1999 January 20 - Correspondence, Legal Files and News Clippings, 1998-1999 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Sheppard, Mark A., Executed 1999 January 20 - Constituent Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Fry, Tony Leslie, Executed 1999 February 4 - (No Clemency Request Made) Constituent Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Quesinberry, George, Executed 1999 March 9 - Correspondence and News Clippings, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Quesinberry, George, Executed 1999 March 9 - Petition and Exhibits to Clemency Petition, 1999 March 2 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Quesinberry, George, Executed 1999 March 9- Exhibits to Clemency Petition, 1999 March 2 (copy) (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Quesinberry, George, Executed 1999 March 9- Exhibits to Clemency Petition, 1999 March 2 (copy) (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Quesinberry, George, Executed 1999 March 9 - Correspondence, Legal Files and Meeting Notes, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Quesinberry, George, Executed 1999 March 9 - Constituent Correspondence, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Fisher, David Lee, Executed 1999 March 25 - Clemency Petition (2 copies) (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Fisher, David Lee, Executed 1999 March 25- Clemency Appendix, Volume 1 (Box 11)
  - Fisher, David Lee, Executed 1999 March 25 - Clemency Appendix, Volume 2 (Box 12)
  - Fisher, David Lee, Executed 1999 March 25 - Clemency Appendix, Volume 3 (Box 12)
  - Fisher, David Lee, Executed 1999 March 25 - Correspondence, Meeting Notes and Legal Files, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Fisher, David Lee, Executed 1999 March 25 - Constituent Correspondence, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Chichester, Carl, Executed 1999 April 13 - Correspondence, Legal Files, Meeting Notes and Newspaper Clippings, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Chichester, Carl, Executed 1999 April 13 - Constituent Correspondence, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Jenkins, Arthur, Executed 1999 April 20 - Correspondence, Legal Files and Meeting Notes, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Jenkins, Arthur, Executed 1999 April 20 - Correspondence, Legal Files and Meeting Notes, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Jenkins, Arthur, Executed 1999 April 20 - Correspondence, Legal Files and Meeting Notes, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Jenkins, Arthur, Executed 1999 April 20 - Constituent Correspondence, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Payne, Eric, Executed 1999 April 28 (No Clemency Request Made; Payne did not appeal death sentence) - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Yeatts, Ronald Dale, Executed 1999 April 29 - Correspondence and Legal Files, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Yeatts, Ronald Dale, Executed 1999 April 29 - Correspondence and Legal Files, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Yeatts, Ronald Dale, Executed 1999 April 29- Constituent Correspondence, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Strickler, Tommy David, Executed 1999 July 21 - Correspondence, Legal Files, Meeting Notes and Newspaper Clippings, 1998-1999 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Strickler, Tommy David, Executed 1999 July 21 - Clemency Petition documents (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Strickler, Tommy David, Executed 1999 July 21- Supplement to Clemency Petition, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Strickler, Tommy David, Executed 1999 July 21 - Correspondence and Legal Files, 1998-1999 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Strickler, Tommy David, Executed 1999 July 21- Supplement to Clemency Petition, 1999 (copy two) (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Strickler, Tommy David, Executed 1999 July 21- Clemency Petition, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Strickler, Tommy David, Executed 1999 July 21 - Partial Trial Transcript (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Strickler, Tommy David, Executed 1999 July 21 - Constituent Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Williams, Marlon Dwayne, Executed 1999 August 17- Correspondence, Legal Files and Meeting Notes, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Williams, Marlon Dwayne, Executed 1999 August 17- Clemency Petition, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Williams, Marlon Dwayne, Executed 1999 August 17 - Constituent Correspondence, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Mueller, Everett Ray, Executed 1999 September 16 - Legal Files, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Mueller, Everett Ray, Executed 1999 September 16 - Clemency Petition, 1999 (copy one) (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Mueller, Everett Ray, Executed 1999 September 16 - Clemency Petition, 1999 (copy two) (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Mueller, Everett Ray, Executed 1999 September 16 - Constituent Correspondence, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Joseph, Jason Matthew, Executed 1999 October 19 - Correspondence, Legal Files and Newspaper Clippings, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Royal, Jr., Thomas Lee, Executed 1999 November 9 - Correspondence, Legal Files and Newspaper Clippings, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Royal, Jr., Thomas Lee, Executed 1999 November 9 - Clemency Petition, 1999 November 4 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Graham, Andre, Executed 1999 December 9 - Correspondence, Legal Files and Meeting Notes, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Graham, Andre, Executed 1999 December 9 - Correspondence, Legal Files and Meeting Notes, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- 2000, Extent: 9 boxes. (Box 17-26)
  2000 clemency files include: Douglas Christopher Thomas (executed 2000 January 10), Steve Edward Roach (executed 2000 January 13), Lonnie Weeks, Jr. (executed 2000 March 16), Michael D. Clagett (executed 2000 July 6), Russell William Burkett (executed 2000 August 30), Derek Rocco Barnebei (executed 2000 September 14), Bobby Lee Ramdass (executed 2000 October 10), and Christopher C. Goins (executed 2000 December 6).
  - Thomas, Douglas Christopher, Executed 2000 January 10 - Correspondence, Legal Files and Meeting Notes, 1999-2000 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Thomas, Douglas Christopher, Executed 2000 January 10 - Correspondence, Legal Files and Meeting Notes, 1999-2000 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Thomas, Douglas Christopher, Executed 2000 January 10 - Correspondence, Legal Files and Meeting Notes, 1999-2000 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Thomas, Douglas Christopher, Executed 2000 January 10 - Correspondence, Legal Files and Meeting Notes, 1999-2000 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Thomas, Douglas Christopher, Executed 2000 January 10 - Correspondence, Legal Files and Meeting Notes, 1999-2000 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Thomas, Douglas Christopher, Executed 2000 January 10 - Constituent Correspondence, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Thomas, Douglas Christopher, Executed 2000 January 10 - Constituent Correspondence, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Thomas, Douglas Christopher, Executed 2000 January 10 - Constituent Correspondence, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Thomas, Douglas Christopher, Executed 2000 January 10 - Constituent Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Thomas, Douglas Christopher, Executed 2000 January 10 - Constituent Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Thomas, Douglas Christopher, Executed 2000 January 10 - Constituent Correspondence, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Thomas, Douglas Christopher, Executed 2000 January 10 - Constituent Correspondence, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Thomas, Douglas Christopher, Executed 2000 January 10 - Constituent Correspondence, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Roach, Steve Edward, Executed 2000 January 13 - Correspondence to Governor Gilmore from Roach, Roach's wife and from Victim's family members, 1999-2000 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Roach, Steve Edward, Executed 2000 January 13 - Legal Files and Meeting Notes, 1999-2000 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Roach, Steve Edward, Executed 2000 January 13 - Clemency Petition, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Roach, Steve Edward, Executed 2000 January 13 - Correspondence, Meeting Notes and Copy of Clemency, 1999-2000 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Roach, Steve Edward, Executed 2000 January 13 - Correspondence and Legal Files, 1999-2000 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Roach, Steve Edward, Executed 2000 January 13 - Correspondence and Legal Files, 1999-2000 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Roach, Steve Edward, Executed 2000 January 13 - Constituent Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Roach, Steve Edward, Executed 2000 January 13 - Constituent Correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Weeks, Jr., Lonnie, Executed 2000 March 16 - Correspondence, Legal Files, Meeting Notes and Clemency Petition, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Weeks, Jr., Lonnie, Executed 2000 March 16 - Appendix to Clemency Petition, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Weeks, Jr., Lonnie, Executed 2000 March 16 - Correspondence and Clemency Petition, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Weeks, Jr., Lonnie, Executed 2000 March 16 - Correspondence and Clemency Petition, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Weeks, Jr., Lonnie, Executed 2000 March 16 - Correspondence and Meeting Notes, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Weeks, Jr., Lonnie, Executed 2000 March 16 - Constituent Correspondence, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Clagett, Michael D., Executed 2000 July 6 - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Burkett, Russell William, Executed 2000 August 30 - Correspondence, Legal Files and Meeting Notes, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Burkett, Russell William, Executed 2000 August 30 - Correspondence, Legal Files and Meeting Notes, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Burkett, Russell William, Executed 2000 August 30 - Correspondence, Legal Files and Meeting Notes, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Burkett, Russell William, Executed 2000 August 30 - Correspondence, Legal Files and Meeting Notes, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Barnebei, Derek Rocco, Executed 2000 September 14 - Correspondence and Legal Files, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Barnebei, Derek Rocco, Executed 2000 September 14 - Correspondence and Legal Files, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Barnebei, Derek Rocco, Executed 2000 September - Clemency Petition, 2000 July17 (Box 23)
  - Barnebei, Derek Rocco, Executed 2000 September - Exhibits to Clemency Petition, 2000 July 17 (copy one) (Box 23)
  - Barnebei, Derek Rocco, Executed 2000 September - Exhibits to Clemency Petition, 2000 July 17 (copy two) (Box 23)
  - Barnebei, Derek Rocco, Executed 2000 September 14 - Correspondence and Legal Files, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Barnebei, Derek Rocco, Executed 2000 September 14 - Correspondence and Legal Files, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Barnebei, Derek Rocco, Executed 2000 September 14 - Correspondence and Legal Files, 2000 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Barnebei, Derek Rocco, Executed 2000 September 14 - Newspaper Articles, 2000 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Barnebei, Derek Rocco, Executed 2000 September 14 - Constituent Correspondence, 2000 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Ramdass, Bobby Lee, Executed 2000 October 10 - Clemency Petition, 1999 November 19 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Ramdass, Bobby Lee, Executed 2000 October 10 - Appendix to Clemency Petition, 1999 November 19 (copy one) (Box 24)
  - Ramdass, Bobby Lee, Executed 2000 October 10 - Appendix to Clemency Petition, 1999 November 19 (copy two) (Box 24)
  - Ramdass, Bobby Lee, Executed 2000 October 10 - Appendix to Clemency Petition, 1999 November 19 (copy three) (Box 24)
  - Ramdass, Bobby Lee, Executed 2000 October 10 - Correspondence and Legal Files, 1999 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Ramdass, Bobby Lee, Executed 2000 October 10 - Correspondence, Legal Files and Copy of Clemency Petition, 1999 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Ramdass, Bobby Lee, Executed 2000 October 10 - Appendix to Clemency Petition, 1999 November 19 (Box 25)
  - Ramdass, Bobby Lee, Executed 2000 October 10 - Correspondence, Legal Files and Meeting Notes, 2000 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Ramdass, Bobby Lee, Executed 2000 October 10 - Correspondence, Legal Files and Meeting Notes, 2000 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Ramdass, Bobby Lee, Executed 2000 October 10 - Constituent Correspondence, 2000 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Goins, Christopher C., Executed 2000 December 6 - Correspondence and Clemency Petition, 2000 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Goins, Christopher C., Executed 2000 December 6 - Correspondence and Clemency Petition, 2000 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Goins, Christopher C., Executed 2000 December 6 - Correspondence and Clemency Petition, 2000 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Goins, Christopher C., Executed 2000 December 6 - Correspondence and Clemency Petition, 2000 (Box 26, Folder 4)
- 2001, Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 26-27)
  2001 clemency files include: Thomas Wayne Akers (executed 2001 March 1), Walter Mickens, Jr. (execution scheduled for 2001 April 17 but stayed by United States Supreme Court; executed 2002 June 12), and Christopher James Beck (executed 2001 October 18).
  - Akers, Thomas Wayne, Executed 2001 March 1 - Correspondence and Legal Files, 2001 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Akers, Thomas Wayne, Executed 2001 March 1 - Correspondence and Legal Files, 2001 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Akers, Thomas Wayne, Executed 2001 March - Appendix to Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus, Supreme Court of Virginia (copy one) (Box 26)
  - Akers, Thomas Wayne, Executed 2001 March - Appendix to Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus, Supreme Court of Virginia (copy two) (Box 27)
  - Mickens, Jr., Walter, Execution Scheduled for 2001 April 17(Stayed by United States Supreme Court) - Correspondence and Legal Files, 2001 [Note: Mickens executed 2002 June 12] (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Mickens, Jr., Walter, Execution Scheduled for 2001 April 17(Stayed by United States Supreme Court) - Correspondence, Legal Files and Meeting Notes, 2001 [Note: Mickens executed 2002 June 12] (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Beck, Christopher James, Executed 2001 October 18 - Clemency Petition, 2001 (copy one) (Box 27)
  - Beck, Christopher James, Executed 2001 October 18 - Clemency Petition, 2001 (copy two) (Box 27)
  - Beck, Christopher James, Executed 2001 October 18 - Correspondence, Legal Files, Meeting Notes and Constituent Correspondence, 2001 (Box 27, Folder 3)